Sound Recordings of Museum-Related Events
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Sound Recordings of Video Viewpoints, 1978-present
  - "Toy War Heats Up", November 15, 1999; PERSONALITY: RTMark PLACE: Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art PARTICIPANTS: Reverend Billy; Santas Against eToys; The Hungry March Band; spokespersons for eToy; Leonardo Rhizome; eviltoy; The Thing; Praystation; ivillage.com; the Electronic Disturbance Theater; Fakeshop SPONSOR: The Contemporary Arts Council of The MoMA, the National Endowment for the Arts, The New York State Council on the Arts, and the MacArthur Foundation DATA: 2 90 Minute Standard Audio Cassettes RELATED MATERIAL: Please visit the Department of Media for Transcript and Program Notes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: January, 2000 (Item vv.99.9b)
  - Untitled, January 24, 2000; PERSONALITY: Nelson Henricks PLACE: Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: The Contemporary Arts Council of The MoMA, the National Endowment for the Arts, The New York State Council on the Arts, and the MacArthur Foundation DATA: 2 90 Minute Standard Audio Cassettes RELATED MATERIAL: Please visit the Department of Media for Transcript and Program Notes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: January, 2000 (Item vv2000.1a)
  - Untitled, January 24, 2000; PERSONALITY: Nelson Henricks PLACE: Titus Theater 2, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: The Contemporary Arts Council of The MoMA, the National Endowment for the Arts, The New York State Council on the Arts, and the MacArthur Foundation DATA: 2 90 Minute Standard Audio Cassettes RELATED MATERIAL: Please visit the Department of Media for Transcript and Program Notes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: January, 2000 (Item vv2000.1b)
  - Untitled, February 28, 2000; PERSONALITY: George Legrady PLACE: Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2 DATA: 1 90 Minute Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: lecture RELATED MATERIAL: Please see Transcripts, Folder 182 DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: June 19, 2000 (Item vv2000.2)
  - "New Words / New Work", May 14, 2001; PERSONALITY: Seth Price; Laura Parnes PLACE: Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London; Seth Price; Laura Parnes DATA: One standard 90-minute audiocassette SUMMARY: Lecture RELATED MATERIAL: Please see Transcripts, Folder 196 DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: May 31, 2001 (Item vv2001.1)
  - Untitled, May 15, 2001; PERSONALITY: Iñigo Manglano-Ovalle PLACE: Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 2 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London; Iñigo Manglano-Ovalle DATA: One standard 90-minute audiocassette SUMMARY: Lecture RELATED MATERIAL: Please see Transcripts, Folder 188 DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: May 31, 2001 (Item vv2001.2)
  - "Presenting Artists", October 22, 2001; PERSONALITY: John Pilson PLACE: Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London; John Pilson DATA: standard audiocassette SUMMARY: lecture DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 9, 2001 (Item vv2001.3)
  - "Presenting Artists", October 22, 2001; PERSONALITY: Kevin and Jennifer McCoy PLACE: Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London; Kevin McCoy; Jennifer McCoy DATA: standard audiocassette SUMMARY: lecture DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 9, 2001 (Item vv2001.4)
  - Untitled, January 14, 2002; PERSONALITY: Janine Cirincione / Michael Ferraro and Feng Mengbo PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art, Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: New York Sate Council on the Arts; Contemporary Art Council, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: March 2002 (Item vv2002.1a)
  - Untitled, January 14, 2002; PERSONALITY: Janine Cirincione / Michael Ferraro and Feng Mengbo PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art, Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: New York Sate Council on the Arts; Contemporary Art Council, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: March 2002 (Item vv2002.1b)
  - Untitled, February 25, 2002; PERSONALITY: Torsten Zenas Burns and Katarzyna Kozyra PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art, Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: New York Sate Council on the Arts; Contemporary Art Council, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: March 2002 (Item vv2002.2)
  - Untitled, March 18, 2002; PERSONALITY: Eleanor Antin and Tania Bruguera PLACE: Donnell Library Center Auditorium PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: New York Sate Council on the Arts; Contemporary Art Council, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One 90-minute Standard Audio Cassette DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: April 24, 2002 (Item vv2002.3)
  - Untitled, April 8, 2002; PERSONALITY: Ron Kuivila and Graham Harwood PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art, Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London, Associate Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: New York Sate Council on the Arts; Contemporary Art Council, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: April 29, 2002 (Item vv2002.4a)
  - Untitled, April 8, 2002; PERSONALITY: Ron Kuivila and Graham Harwood PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art, Roy and Niuta Titus Theater 1 PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London, Associate Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art SPONSOR: New York Sate Council on the Arts; Contemporary Art Council, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: Two 90-minute Standard Audio Cassettes DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: April 29, 2002 (Item vv2002.4b)
  - Untitled, October 20, 2003; PERSONALITY: Doug Aitken PLACE: Gramercy Theater, Manhattan PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London, Associate Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art, Doug Aitken SPONSOR: New York State Council on the Arts, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One standard 90-minute cassette tape SUMMARY: Video Viewpoints is a series in which independent video artists present and discuss their work, technique and theories. Doug Aitken gives a slide presentation, screens short films and answers audience questions. DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2003.1)
  - "Love Will Tear Us Apart", October 27, 2003; PERSONALITY: Sue de Beer PLACE: Gramercy Theater, Manhattan PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London, Associate Curator, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art, Sue de Beer, Alyssa Bennett SPONSOR: New York State Council on the Arts, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One standard 90-minute cassette tape SUMMARY: Video Viewpoints is a series in which independent video artist present and discuss their work, technique and theories. Sue de Beer and Alyssa Bennett both read short stories in a performative manner followed by an audience question and answer session. RELATED MATERIAL: DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2003.2)
  - "An Evening with Yang Fudong", January 26, 2004; PERSONALITY: Yang Fudong PLACE: Gramercy Theater, Manhattan PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London, Associate Curator in the Department of Film and Video, Yang Fudong SPONSOR: New York State Council on the Arts, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One standard 90-minute cassette tape. SUMMARY: Video Viewpoints is a series in which independent video artist present and discuss their work, technique and theories. DONOR: Video Program, The Museum of Modern Art TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2004.1)
  - "Mediascopes-"An Evening with Wang Jianwei", February 9, 2004; NOTE: The recording starts mid-lecture, therefore cutting off the introduction and beginning remarks.; PERSONALITY: Wang Jianwei PLACE: Gramercy Theater, Manhattan PARTICIPANTS: Wang Jianwei SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video, Department of Education DATA: One Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: The artist Wang Jianwei discusses his artistic influences and shows short video recordings of is performance pieces. DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2004.2)
  - "Mediascopes-"An Evening with Bjrn Melhus", November 24, 2003; PERSONALITY: Bjrn Melhus PLACE: Gramercy Theater, Manhattan PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in Department of Film and Video; Bjrn Melhus SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art DATA: One Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Program presented by Bjrn Melhus consisting of several video pieces representing his single channel works, narrative works and installation pieces. The lecture is followed by a question and answer session with the artist. DONOR: Department of Education TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004; NOTE: Please see Supplemental Materials for event pamphlet. (Item vv2004.3)
  - "Music and Media: Three Evenings", September 23, 2004; PERSONALITY: Laurie Anderson PLACE: CUNY, Graduate Center SERIES: Music and Media Tapes PARTICIPANTS: Laurie Anderson, Greil Marcus SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: 1-Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Informal discussion between Greil Marcus and Laurie Anderson regarding Anderson's work, her influences and her career choices. RELATED MATERIAL: Please see Transcripts, Folder 104; vv84.3, vv94.a and vv.94b DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2004.4, vv2004.4D)
  - "Music and Media: Three Evenings", September 30, 2004; NOTE: The recording cuts off before the discussion ends.; PERSONALITY: Michel Gondry PLACE: CUNY Graduate Center SERIES: Music and Media Tapes PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Michel Gondry, Ed Halter SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video, CUNY Graduate Center DATA: 1-Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Discussion between Michel Gondry and Ed Halter regarding the works of Michel Gondry, his artistic influences, biography and current projects. RELATED MATERIAL: Please see Transcripts, Folder 105 DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2004.5, vv2004.5D)
  - "Music and Media: Three Evenings", October 7, 2004; NOTE: The beginning portion of the recording is cut-off.; PERSONALITY: Brian Eno PLACE: CUNY Graduate Center SERIES: Music and Media Tapes PARTICIPANTS: Brian Eno, Todd Haynes SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video, CUNY Graduate Center DATA: 2-Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tapes SUMMARY: Discussion between Brian Eno and Todd Haynes regarding Eno's work, influences and biography. RELATED MATERIAL: Please see Transcripts, Folder 106 DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv2004.6a, vv2004.6aD)
  - "Music and Media: Three Evenings", October 7, 2004; NOTE: The beginning portion of the recording is cut-off.; PERSONALITY: Brian Eno PLACE: CUNY Graduate Center SERIES: Music and Media Tapes PARTICIPANTS: Brian Eno, Todd Haynes SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video, CUNY Graduate Center DATA: 2-Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tapes SUMMARY: Discussion between Brian Eno and Todd Haynes regarding Eno's work, influences and biography. RELATED MATERIAL: Transcript Box 1 DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: October 2004 (Item vv.2004.6b, vv2004.6bD)
  - "An Evening with Kutlug Ataman", December 9, 2003; NOTE: The first tape is completely blank. The second tape contains the second portion of the lecture-a question and answer session with the artist.; PERSONALITY: Kutlug Ataman PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope PARTICIPANTS: Kuthug Ataman SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: 2 Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tapes DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.7a)
  - "An Evening with Kutlug Ataman", December 9, 2003; NOTE: The first tape is completely blank. The second tape contains the second portion of the lecture-a question and answer session with the artist.; PERSONALITY: Kutlug Ataman PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope PARTICIPANTS: Kuthug Ataman SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: 2 Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tapes DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.7b)
  - "An Evening with Carey Young", January 27, 2003; PERSONALITY: Carey Young PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Carey Young SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: 2 Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tapes SUMMARY: Lecture and discussion of the works of film artist Carey Young. DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.8a)
  - "An Evening with Carey Young", January 27, 2003; PERSONALITY: Carey Young PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Carey Young SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: 2 Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tapes SUMMARY: Lecture and discussion of the works of film artist Carey Young. DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.8b)
  - "Second Mediascope Presentation", November 11, 2002; PERSONALITY: Leah Gilliam PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope/Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Leah Gilliam SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: One Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Film artist Leah Gilliam gives an informal presentation about her work with specific focus placed on Agenda for a Landscape(2002). DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.9a)
  - "Second Mediascope Presentation", November 11, 2002; PERSONALITY: Leah Gilliam PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope/Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Leah Gilliam SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: One Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Film artist Leah Gilliam gives an informal presentation about her work with specific focus placed on Agenda for a Landscape(2002). DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.9b)
  - "An Evening with Paul Pfeiffer", May 12, 2003; NOTE: The beginning of the lecture is cut-off in the recording.; PERSONALITY: Paul Pfeiffer PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope/Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Paul Pfeiffer SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: One Standard 90-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Film artist Paul Pfeiffer gives an informal presentation about his work. DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.10)
  - "An Evening with Guy Richards Smit", November 25, 2002; NOTE: The original recording was taped over music, thus the end of Side 1 and all of Side 2 have music on the tape. The duplicate copy is just the recording of Guy Richards Smit.; PERSONALITY: Guy Richards Smit PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope/Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Sally Berger, Assistant Curator Department of Film and Video; Guy Richards Smit SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: One 60-Minute Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: A screening and lecture with performance artist Guy Richards Smit DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.11, vv2004.11D)
  - "An Evening with Miranda July", February 24, 2003; PERSONALITY: Miranda July PLACE: Gramercy Theater SERIES: Mediascope/Cineprobe PARTICIPANTS: Introduction: Barbara London, Assistant Curator in the Department of Film and Video; Miranda July SPONSOR: Department of Film and Video DATA: One 90-Minute Standard Audiocassette Tape SUMMARY: Performance and lecture by artist Miranda July. Discussion follows the presentation. DONOR: Department of Film and Video TRANSFERRED TO ARCHIVES: November 2004 (Item vv2004.12)
  - "Hani Rashid and Lise Anne Couture", PERSONALITY: Hani Rashid and Lise Anne Couture. PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art SERIES: Technology in the Nineties: The Human/Machine Interface PARTICIPANTS: Hani Rashid, architect; Lise Anne Couture, architect; Barbara London, curator, Department of Media, The Museum of Modern Art. DATA: 1 90 Minute Standard Audio Cassette. SUMMARY: Hani Rashid and Lise Anne Couture discuss the various ways preexisting spatial relationships affect their work. RELATED MATERIAL: vv2006.5a, vv2006.5b. DONOR: Department of Film and Video. (Item vv2007.1)
  - "Shirin Neshat", March 20, 2000; PERSONALITY: Shirin Neshat PLACE: The Museum of Modern Art. SERIES: Video Viewpoints PARTICIPANTS: Sally Berger, curatorial assistant, Department of Film and Video, The Museum of Modern Art. DATA: 1 Standard Audio Cassette SUMMARY: Shirin Neshat speaks about her background in photography and her evolution into video. RELATED MATERIAL: 2003.25a, 2003.25b, 2006.24; Please see Transcripts, Folder 193 DONOR: Department of Film and Video. (Item vv2007.2)